Today we will compare Tata AIG's health
insurance plans. So, Tata AIG has three
health insurance plans about which
we will talk today - Tata AIG Medicare,
Medicare Premier, and Medicare Plus. We will
talk about these three plans in detail
and compare the
benefits, features,
and premiums of these three plans. So,
before starting the video, I would
like to introduce myself. My
name is Gurleen Kaur Tikku. I am a
Certified Financial Planner. I have been
associated with the insurance industry for the last 18 years
and every week I bring you videos to make
your personal financial life
happier. Because our company's
tagline is also 'Creating a Wealth of
Happiness'. Let's move on to today's video:
Comparison of Tata AIG Health Insurance
Plans. We will talk about Tata AIG
Medicare, Medicare Premier,
and Medicare Plus. So, let
me tell you about all three plans, which are Medicare and
Medicare Premier. These are the base health
insurance plans where you can  Medicare
Plus is a super top up policy, which means
you can take a policy with a deductible.
Now we will talk about its basic eligibility
criteria. So the minimum entry age is 18
years and maximum is 65 years in all the three policies.
Your children can be added as a
dependent child in the policy. The minimum and
maximum sum assured for EIG Medicare is Rs 5
lakh and the maximum sum assured is Rs 20
lakh. For EIG Medicare Premier, the
minimum sum assured is Rs 5 lakh and the maximum is Rs 3
crore. Medicare Plus, as I
told you, is a super top up policy, so it
comes with a deductible. That means,
if you are taking a policy of Rs 5 lakh, then there is a deductible of Rs 3 and 5 lakh. If you are taking a policy of Rs 10 lakh, then there
is a deductible of Rs 5 and 10 lakh. If you are taking a policy of Rs 15 lakh, then there is a deductible of Rs
5 and 10 lakh. If you are taking a policy of Rs
15 lakh, then there are all
three deductible options available, 5, 10 and 15. Similarly, the
maximum will be Rs 5.  Up to 100k means up to 1 crore,
so with 1 crore, all four deductible options of 5, 10, 15, 20
are available, which is good.
What happens in most of the policies is that the
deductible option means that you have to
pay first before claiming from the super topper policy,
whether you
pay from corporate cover or from any other health
insurance policy, then
usually the maximum is 10 lakh in most of the policies,
but the good thing here is
that it is 20 lakh, so what will happen with this, your
premium will reduce, if suppose you
took a base policy of 20 lakh and you
take a super top up of 1 crore, then your total
premium outgo will reduce as compared to the
base policy of 20 lakh, if you take a super top up
of 1 crore with a deductible of 10 lakh, then the
premium will be higher because the
initial amount has to be borne more.
Now let's talk about no claim bonus.
You get no claim bonus in Medicare policy
if you make a claim  If you do not take 50,
maximum 100% and it will reduce if you
take a claim in the future.
In Medicare Premier also, at 50, you
get a maximum 100% no claim bonus every year and
it will reduce in case of claim. No claim
bonus is there in Medicare Plus also at 50 in
case of no claim in a year and maximum
100% and it will reduce if you take a
claim in the future. Usually, there is
no bonus in your super topper policies, so this
bonus is a good thing that there is a bonus in this also. Now let's
talk about room eligibility. There is no restriction in IG
Medicare, Medicare Premier and
Medicare Plus.
You can take any room
and age but actual pay will be made.
Day care procedures are also covered.
Day care procedures are those where due to
advancement in pay science, your
24-hour hospitalization is not necessary. So, there are
many procedures
which you  Same day discharge is done. There
are total 540 procedures
covered in all the three policies. AYUSH hospitalization under day care
is AYUSH, Ayurveda,
Unani, Siddha, Homeopathy, its
hospitalization is also covered.
Refill benefit is available in all the three plans.
Refill benefit is not available in Medicare and Medicare Premier in Super Topup.
So, it is refilled if your base
sum assured is exhausted, even after that
you will need to make another claim in the same year, then the
insurance company refills the equal to base sum assured
again. So,
in this policy 100% of sum assured will be
refilled only once. Emergency road ambulance is
₹1000 per hospitalization in Medicare Premier. The maximum amount
you can claim is emergency road ambulance.
In Medicare Premier, it is from ₹5000 to ₹3000. The
limit is defined according to the sum assured.
In Medicare Plus, it is again
₹1000. Emergency air ambulance.  Where medical
evacuation has to be done, in cases
where a road ambulance or surface ambulance
is not possible, in that case emergency air
ambulance is required. Tata EIG is
not covered in Medicare and Medicare Plus. Your
emergency road ambulance is covered only in Medicare Premier. The
company provides you a complimentary wellness test,
you can get your health checkup done so that
you can take care of your health.
In Medicare and Medicare Premier, you will be given 1 per sum
insured every year
and in Medicare Plus, 1 per sum
insured will be given, maximum ₹1000000 in 2
years, more than that will not be given.
Complimentary annual health checkup, high end
diagnostic test. Firstly, we talk about
a basic health checkup which is given,
complete annual, that is covered. After that, there are
some high end tests, some more
advanced diagnostic tests, they are
not covered in Medicare and Medicare Plus, but are
covered in Medicare Premier. Let us understand what if  If your
policy is above 50 lakhs, then you will be
given 25000 listed tests which are high end
diagnostic tests, the complete list is in it
and if the policy is of 75 lakhs or above 75 lakhs, then the
insurance company will bear ₹5000000
Accidental Death Benefit This is
not covered in Medicare and Medicare Plus
but is covered in Medicare Premier
Accidental Death Benefit If death occurs due to
accident and the accident
is fatal, then the nominee will receive 100% and 50
lakhs whichever is lower, then that amount will be
received by the nominee Pre and Post
Hospitalization So the expenses before the hospital
and the expenses after will
also be covered In TIE IG
Medicare Plan, 60 days
pre-hospitalization expenses and 90 days post-
hospitalization will be covered TIE IG
Medicare Premium is also 6090 If
your sum shot is above 75 lakhs, then the
post  Hospitalization will increase from 90 to
200. In IG Medicare Plus
also there are 60 and 90. 60 days pre and 90 days
post hospitalization expenses will be covered.
Modern
treatments and robotic surgeries are
also covered. There is
some limit in Medicare and Medicare Premier in the base policies. It will be
covered as per the limit. It is not
covered in Medicare Plus.
Now we will talk about non-payable items
which are also called consumer items. So, in all the
policies of IG, Medicare, Medicare
Premier and Medicare Plus,
non-payable items are covered.
Next we will talk about deductible.
Deductible is the initial amount which
you pay before the insurance
policy kicks in. That deductible option is
not available in both the base policies.
In IG Super Topup, I had told you that a maximum
deductible of Rs 20 lakh is available.
So whatever sum you are taking, take it.  Yes, you
can take a base policy with an initial amount
or you can claim from corporate cover
or you can pay it yourself to reduce
your premium. OPD cover
is not covered in Medicare.
OPD cover is there in your Medicare premium, that means
your OPD coverage starts after two years, it
depends on your sum assured.
If your sum assured is up to Rs 50 lakh, then
you get an OPD benefit of Rs 5,000 in a year after
two years and if it is Rs 75 lakh, then an
OPD benefit of Rs 7500 is given.
You can take an OPD benefit of maximum Rs 2,000,000 after two continuous years of
policies.
This feature is not available in Medicare Plus. There is
no copayment in all the three policies.
So now we will talk about the benefit of compassionate travel.
So, compassionate travel means that
if you are hospitalized for more than 5 days
and your family members  If you do not have money and
are away from home, then in that case the company will
bear the expenses so that your family members can
reach you. This cost of yours will be covered in Medicare Premier.
If the sum assured is ₹50 lakh, then
your cost will be covered there.
If the sum assured is up to ₹75 lakh, then
₹5000000 will also be given
for compassionate travel. This much benefit will be given to bring your family members to
you.
And if you have taken global cover, that is, a
policy above ₹50 lakh and
global cover is applicable, in that case, you will be
given an economy fare ticket to take you there
so that your family members can reach you.
Maternity expenses are not in the Medicare plan, they are
in Medicare Premier. If
anyone wants maternity coverage, then they
can look at Medicare Premier. Let us see
what all coverage is there for maternity in Medicare Premier. There is a
clause in it that
you get continuous travel for 4 years.  The policy will have to be run
after that your maternity benefit will kick in,
meaning the waiting period for maternity is
four years and the coverage here is if
your sum is short up to 50 lakhs then the fixed
benefit is 0000, if your coverage is 75 lakhs
and above then you will be given ₹1 lakh age
delivery cost, above this you will
also be given newborn baby expenses, if the policy is up to 50 lakhs then it will be
50000, if the policy is 75 lakhs and above then it will be
1 lakh, if the baby is a girl then it will be
60000 and 120000, above this whatever medically
necessary treatment is there, that is suppose
any treatment of the baby is done in the hospital
then the insurance company will cover that too and
along with that the first year vaccine will also be paid to you
up to ₹1000000, along with that the first year
vaccine will also be covered ₹10 for baby boy
and ₹1500000 for baby girl. Now let's talk about
global cover, suppose if you get any
illness done in India  If
you want to get treatment outside India, then
that is also covered
in Medicare in your policies. Your
listed illness should be diagnosed
in India and you
can get treatment outside. It
is covered in Medicare as well as Medicare Premier. The
visa cost in Medicare Premier will also be covered and it is also
covered in Medicare Plus. This
is a unique feature.
You will not see global coverage in many super topper policies,
so it is covered in Medicare Plus as well. It is an
optional cover. You
can get it on by paying an additional premium. Global
cover. Now let's talk about waiting periods.
What waiting periods will apply
in your policy? The initial waiting period
is 30 days in all three policies.
You cannot avail planned hospitalization for 30 days.
Slow growing illnesses are
24 months in all three policies. After 24 months, your
slow growing illnesses will be covered. Pre-
assisting conditions are also covered in IG Medicare.
36 months and in TI IG Medicare
Premier it is 24 months and in TI AG
Medicare Plus it is 24 months so any
pre-exiting condition that you are
disclosing, any pre-existing condition that you already have, will be
covered only after this much time.
Lastly, we will talk about the price.
Here for the price, I have taken the age as 45
and 40 for adults and on a policy of Rs 10 lakh, the
premium will be Rs 2929 for Medicare
and Rs 2619 for Medicare Premier,
so there is not much difference but
your benefits increase a lot
in Medicare premium and if you take their super top up
policy of Medicare Plus 1 crore
and
take it with Rs 10 lakh deductible, then the premium is
only Rs 8171, so you can take the combination of Rs 10
lakh plus 1 crore as you feel is right, according to
your age,
according to your family size, according to your medical
condition.  You can make a combination
and take a policy. So this was
my comparison of Tata IG plans.
We have tried to cover all the points. If you have any
feedback in this video,
please let us know. If you found the video useful,
please share it with your friends and
family. And tell me on what I should make the next video. Please
help in the comment section.
And before leaving, a quick reminder. If
you have not yet subscribed to our channel, do
subscribe so that you get the
right information at the right time. See you
in the next video. Stay safe, take care.
Bye Bye.